Guide to the American Association of Family and Consumer Sciences records, 1899-2008.
American Association of Family and Consumer Sciences records,
- Series XIII. Home Economics History
  - Minutes of the Domestic Economy Committee of the Women's Education Association/Household Aid Company, 1903-1905; 2 volumes (Box 168)
  - The Metric System of Weights and Measures, M.J. Watts, circa 1922 (Box 168)
  - Clippings and Recipes Gathered from Friends and Neighbors by Ann E. Langworthy, circa 1917 (Box 168)
  - Bookkeeping log, 1904-1905 (Box 216)
  - Pinking irons (2) (Box 27)
  - Sophie McFarland sewing book, 1902-1904 (Box 106)
  - Sewing models made by Bessie Motter, grades 5 and 6, Toledo, Ohio, circa 1900 (Box 106)
  - Sewing models made by a pupil in public schools in Toledo, Ohio, circa 1900 (Box 106)
  - Notebooks (2) from Carlotta Greer, Manual Training Normal, Pittsburg, Kansas (Box 106)
  - Sewing Book, Stout Institute School, Boston (Box 107)
  - Early method of teaching sewing to children, 1907 (Box 26)
  - Description of the Property of the Stout Institute, Menomonie, Wisconsin, 1911 (Box 26)
  - Scrapbook: Marie Sellers field trip from Washington, D.C. to Columbus, Ohio, 1918 (Box 170)
  - Pratt Institute student workbook by Amy S. Daniels, circa 1902 (Box 8)
  - Scrapbook of original signatures and letters of notables in Home Economics and other areas (Esther McGinnis' book) (Box 8)
  - Home economics history, Kansas State College (Box 194)
  - School lunches (correspondence and publications), 1910-1918 (Box 194)
  - Development of Home Economics in Philadelphia, 1940-06-27 (Box 138)
  - Home economics education
    - Arizona (Box 194)
    - Arizona Homemaking Conference (Box 194)
    - Massachusetts (Box 194)
    - Washington (Box 194)
    - Michigan (Box 194)
    - Texas (Box 194)
    - Oklahoma (Box 194)
    - Missouri (Box 194)
    - New York - "Food, the Teeth and Health" (Box 194)
    - North Carolina (Box 194)
    - Wisconsin (Box 194)
    - Maryland (Box 194)
    - Pennsylvania (Box 194)
    - Louisiana (Box 194)
    - Indiana, 2 folders (Box 194)
    - California (Box 194)
    - Ohio (Box 194)
  - Histories on home economics, circa 1940-1959 (Box 194)
  - Early histories of domestic science education, and home economics pioneers, 1875-1898, circa 1900-1939 (Box 194)
  - Collected material for home economics history, (1952), circa 1900-1959 (Box 194)
  - School lunch article, 1898 (Box 194)
  - Oread Institute (Box 194)
  - Frozen foods industry (Box 194)
  - Speeches from significant participants in home economics
    - Letter explaining origin of files, 2004 (Box 194)
    - 1962, 1965, 1970-1972, 1977-1981, 10 folders (Box 194)
    - 1983-1987, 1989-1992, 1994-1995, 11 folders (Box 194)
    - 1998-1999, 2000, 3 folders (Box 194)
    - International home economics papers, 2 folders (Box 194)
    - Extension service, USDA, land-grant universities (Box 194)
    - U.S. government, universities, NGOs, United Nations, 2 folders (Box 239)
    - International Conference on Nutrition country paper for the United States (Box 239)
  - National Household Economics Association, 1902-1903 (Box 239)
  - Rumford Kitchen exhibit materials (Box 239)
  - Danish cookery class photograph (Box 239)
  - Le Foyer, Paris (postcards) (Box 239)
  - Institut Normal Supérieur d'Economie Ménagère Agricole, Domaine d'Hosseghem-Laeken (postcards) (Box 239)
  - Monthly Bulletin of the Providence Public Library, Providence, Rhode Island, 1898 (Box 239)
  - Bennett College history (Box 239)
  - Virginia Vincenti Oral History Project
    - Cassette Tapes, including microcassettes,(tr.#10783-10820), VHS tapes (V-9019-9023) and CDs (CD-2570-2572) of interviews with various home economists, 1982-2004 (Box 337)
- Series XIV. Addition to Collection (2014)
  This series contains materials that were transferred to RMC from AAFCS Headquarters.
  - Stars of Texas - Thank you; The Ellen H. Richards Circle Dinner Program, 2001-07-01 (Box 327, Folder 1)
  - Fall Leadership Conference; Honor Roll of AAFCS Donors “Giving back to the Profession” Program, 2001-06-30 (Box 327, Folder 1)
  - The “Milwaukee Stars” VIP Reception Invite, 2001-06-20 (Box 327, Folder 1)
  - AAFCS Major Gift and Sponsorship Opportunities Brochure, 2002-2003 (Box 327, Folder 1)
  - “San Diego Stars” Fiesta Invite, 2004 (Box 327, Folder 1)
  - Chalkley-Fenn Public Policy Visiting Scholar Opportunity and Endowment Fund Brochure, 2009 (Box 327, Folder 1)
  - Higher Education Unit (HEU) Brochure; AAFCS Careers Brochure, no date (Box 327, Folder 1)
  - Development Committee Research Pictures, 2007-2008 (Box 327, Folder 2)
  - Press Release from Lincoln County High School, 2001 (Box 327, Folder 2)
  - Infusing Deliberation into a Professional Association Culture: Naming and Framing Obesity as a Public Issue – Final Report Presented to the Kettering Foundation (Box 327, Folder 3)
  - Committees and Liaisons Folder, 2007-2008 (Box 327, Folder 4)
  - Future Search Summit Report, 2005 (Box 327, Folder 4)
  - AAFCS Policy and Procedures Manual and Governance Directory, 2006 (Box 327, Folder 5)
  - Strategic Plan, 2003 (Box 327, Folder 6)
  - Bylaws 2004 (Box 327, Folder 6)
  - Five Year Retrospective of the Massachusetts Avenue Building Assets Fund Grants Program, 1992-1996 (Box 327, Folder 6)
  - Annual Post Convention Reports, 2001-2004 (Box 327, Folder 7)
  - Annual Reports, 2000-2001 (Box 327, Folder 8)
  - Board of Directors Meetings, 2003-2005 (Box 327, Folder 9)
  - Various Committee Meeting Minutes, including senate material and Strategic Plan, 2004-2006 (Box 327, Folder 10)
  - Newsletter for the Leadership of AAFCS International Division Newsletter, 2004-2005 (Box 327, Folder 11)
  - Various Committee Meeting Minutes, 2007-2008 (Box 327, Folder 12)
  - Various Committee Meeting Minutes, 2009 (Box 327, Folder 13)
  - AAFCS Competency and Assessment Exams brochure and Visiting Scholar Opportunity and Endowment Fund brochure, 2009 (Box 327, Folder 14)
  - Color slides, 1970-1979 (Box 327, Folder 15)
  - photos of various AAFCS publications and people, 1994-2004 (Box 327, Folder 16)
  - postcards of National Headquarters, AHEA decals and Stationary (Box 327, Folder 17)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1997 (Box 327, Folder 18)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1998-1999 (Box 327, Folder 19)
  - Certification information, 1997-2000 (Box 327, Folder 20)
  - Helen Judy Bond Collection - book plate (Box 327, Folder 21)
  - Photos and slides of early home economists ( most are not originals) including photos of Ellen Swallow Richards (Box 327, Folder 22)
  - Website of AAFCS, 1998 (Box 327, Folder 23)
  - 9-11 Call to Action – emails, 2011-09-2011-10 (Box 327, Folder 24)
  - Body of Knowledge, 1999 (Box 327, Folder 25)
  - Body of Knowledge, 2003-2004 (Box 327, Folder 26)
  - National Council on Family Relations (NCFR) and AFFCS Conference, 2003 (Box 327, Folder 27)
  - White House Campaign, 2005 (Box 327, Folder 28)
  - Membership and Marketing Committee, 2005-2006 (Box 327, Folder 29)
  - Membership Centennial Directory, 2008 (Box 327, Folder 30)
  - Home Economics quote from Ellen Richards (1904) created in 1966 and cover of Summer 1984 Journal of Home Economics – first cover produced in color (Box 327, Folder 31)
  - Code of Ethics brochure, 1999 (Box 327, Folder 32)
  - postcard sent to members about “A New Era of Action”, no date (Box 327, Folder 32)
  - Biographies of Home Economists, 1927-1948 (Box 327, Folder 33)
  - Portraits of Home Economists taken from AHEA produced book from 1929 (Box 327, Folder 34)
  - Response to MOU, 2002-2004 (Box 328, Folder 1)
  - Potential Archives Site, 1992-2004 (Box 328, Folder 2)
  - MOU Archived material, 1938-2004 (Box 328, Folder 3)
  - AAFCS Smithsonian Issue, 1991 (Box 328, Folder 4)
  - Research Projects-Awards, 1989-2003 (Box 328, Folder 5)
  - Chronology of Events Home Economics, 1923-2002 (Box 328, Folder 6)
  - Affiliate Representatives, 2003-2004 (Box 328, Folder 7)
  - Project Archives, 2004-2005 (Box 328, Folder 8)
  - Gifts to AHEA/AAFCS (Box 328, Folder 9)
  - AAFCS Furniture/Silver (Box 328, Folder 10)
  - AAFCS Cornell Archives MOU, 2004 (Box 328, Folder 11)
  - AAFCS to Cornell University Shipping Inventory (Box 328, Folder 12)
  - Radio Broadcast EH Richards, 1948 (Box 328, Folder 13)
  - History of Archives Committee AAFCS, 2000-2008 (Box 328, Folder 14)
  - Committee Meeting, 2003 (Box 328, Folder 15)
  - Stamp information- Schroeder, 2003 (Box 328, Folder 16)
  - Articles of Incorporation, 1990's (Box 328, Folder 17)
  - Copyright, 1979-1988 (Box 328, Folder 18)
  - Trade Mark patent, 1983 (Box 328, Folder 19)
  - Certification of Incorporation, 1968 (Box 328, Folder 20)
  - Copy Registration, 1987-1990 (Box 328, Folder 21)
  - History of Betty Lamp, 1973-1990 (Box 328, Folder 22)
  - Incorporation, 1951 (Box 328, Folder 23)
  - Art Exhibit and HQRS, 1971-1983 (Box 328, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence with History, 1992-1993 (Box 328, Folder 25)
  - Archival Consultant Final Report, 1988 (Box 328, Folder 26)
  - Records Management, 1977-1988 (Box 328, Folder 27)
  - Establishing and Efficient Records Management Library, 1989 (Box 328, Folder 28)
  - Record of Work Supply, 2000-2002 (Box 328, Folder 29)
  - Oral History Guidelines, 1992-2003 (Box 328, Folder 30)
  - Budget/ Catalogue for supplies, 2002 (Box 328, Folder 31)
  - Certification, 2003 (Box 328, Folder 32)
  - History and Archives Committee, 1988-1989 (Box 328, Folder 33)
  - Ann Chadwick- Kitchen Utensils (Box 328, Folder 34)
  - Chadwick slides, 2002 (Box 328, Folder 35)
  - Chadwick slides, 2002 (Box 328, Folder 36)
  - Negatives (Box 328, Folder 37)
  - Old Projects, 1979 (Box 328, Folder 38)
  - Susan Watson's Information, 1991-2002 (Box 328, Folder 39)
  - History and Archives, 2002 (Box 328, Folder 40)
  - Consultant Report, 1992 (Box 328, Folder 41)
  - Research Issues/Quotes, 2002 (Box 328, Folder 42)
  - 1555 King Street Headquarters, 1989 (Box 328, Folder 43)
  - 20th and Q Headquarters, 1939-1950 (Box 328, Folder 44)
  - Useful Assn. Information 5145 account, 1970-1990 (Box 328, Folder 45)
  - Fellowship and Awards Information, 1927-1970 (Box 328, Folder 46)
  - Silk Coverlet, 2000 (Box 328, Folder 47)
  - Yankelovitch, 1974 (Box 328, Folder 48)
  - International Federation for Home Economics, 1971 (Box 328, Folder 49)
  - Project Taking Charge, 1992 (Box 328, Folder 50)
  - Home Economics- A Pacesetter Profession, 1977-1989 (Box 328, Folder 51)
  - The Spirit of the Lake Placid Founders – script, 1974 (Box 328, Folder 52)
  - Canadian Home Economics Association, 1982-1984 (Box 328, Folder 53)
  - Conference Booklets, 1963-1973 (Box 328, Folder 54)
  - "Critical Sciences" by Virginia Vincenti, 2004 (Box 329, Folder 1)
  - President's Report: Assembly of Delegates, 1973 (Box 329, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1970's (Box 329, Folder 3)
  - Tools for Schools: Project Home Safe, 1993 (Box 329, Folder 4)
  - AHEA Newsletter, 1973 (Box 329, Folder 5)
  - Report: Future Search Summit, 2005 (Box 329, Folder 6)
  - Interview: Merne Samples, 1982 (Box 329, Folder 7)
  - Senate Minutes, 1994-2001 (Box 329, Folder 8)
  - Home Economics in Business, 1987-1994 (Box 329, Folder 9)
  - AAFCS Business Section, 1995-1998 (Box 329, Folder 10)
  - Home Economics Task Force, 1993 (Box 329, Folder 11)
  - Scottsdale Meeting, 1993 (Box 329, Folder 12)
  - Oral History: Mary McDonald, 1921-1995 (Box 329, Folder 13)
  - Reasons for Students to Join AHEA (Box 329, Folder 14)
  - Review of the Massachusetts Avenue Building, 2001 (Box 329, Folder 15)
  - Kindergarten Family Fun Night, 2001 (Box 329, Folder 16)
  - Interim Development Assessment - Volume 1, 1994 (Box 329, Folder 17)
  - Interim Development Assessment - Volume 2, 1994 (Box 329, Folder 18)
  - Press Release: Name Change, 1993-1994 (Box 329, Folder 19)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1996-1997 (Box 329, Folder 20)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1997 (Box 329, Folder 21)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 2000 (Box 329, Folder 22)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 2001-2002 (Box 329, Folder 23)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 2003 (Box 329, Folder 24)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 2004 (Box 329, Folder 25)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 2005-2006 (Box 329, Folder 26)
  - Press Releases, 2001-2004 (Box 329, Folder 27)
  - P.R. Forum, 2003-2004 (Box 329, Folder 28)
  - P.R. Tool Kit, 2002-2004 (Box 329, Folder 29)
  - Early Childhood Initiative Reports and Displays, 1997 (Box 329, Folder 30)
  - Early Childhood Initiative Reports and Displays, 1997 (Box 329, Folder 31)
  - Millenium Project - Requests for Proposals, 1998 (Box 329, Folder 32)
  - Literature Review: Effectiveness of Public School Family and Consumer Sciences Programs, 2004 (Box 329, Folder 33)
  - Marketing Materials, 2004-2005 (Box 329, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence AAFCS, 2004 (Box 329, Folder 35)
  - Strategic Planning, 1995-2003 (Box 329, Folder 36)
  - Vocational Education Legislation, 2003 (Box 329, Folder 37)
  - Correspndence: Massachusetts Department of Education (Box 329, Folder 38)
  - Commemorative Lecture, 2001 (Box 329, Folder 39)
  - American Vocational Technical Education Act Amendments of Bill (H.R. 1853), 1997 (Box 329, Folder 40)
  - Oprah Disparages Home Economics, 2000 (Box 329, Folder 41)
  - Du Pont Company Play: Ellen Swallow, 1948 (Box 329, Folder 42)
  - Public Relations Aids, 1965 (Box 329, Folder 43)
  - Newsletter: The Mint, 2003-2008 (Box 329, Folder 44)
  - Frankel Speech, 2000 (Box 330, Folder 1)
  - Resolution Package, 2000 (Box 330, Folder 2)
  - Project Taking Charge, 1995 (Box 330, Folder 3)
  - Phone-A-Thon, 2005 (Box 330, Folder 4)
  - Officer Reports, 2003-2004 (Box 330, Folder 5)
  - Certification Certificates, 2005 (Box 330, Folder 6)
  - Award Brochures, 2005 (Box 330, Folder 7)
  - Stationary Samples (Box 330, Folder 8)
  - Project Archives Brochures, 2004 (Box 330, Folder 9)
  - Conference Materials, 2005 (Box 330, Folder 10)
  - Membership Contests, 2006 (Box 330, Folder 11)
  - Elementary, Secondary and Adult Education Issues, 2001 (Box 330, Folder 12)
  - AAFCS Literature and Brochures, 1995-2000 (Box 330, Folder 13)
  - Marketing, 2001-2004 (Box 330, Folder 14)
  - Member Needs Survey, 2000 (Box 330, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence - Mailings (Box 330, Folder 16)
  - Publications and Product Catalogs, 1997, 2002 (Box 330, Folder 17)
  - Development Committee Minutes, 1998 (Box 330, Folder 18)
  - Development Committee Minutes, 1998 (Box 330, Folder 19)
  - Development Committee, 1999 (Box 330, Folder 20)
  - Development Committee, 2001-2002 (Box 330, Folder 21)
  - Development Committee, 2005-2006 (Box 330, Folder 22)
  - Development Committee, 2010 (Box 330, Folder 23)
  - AAFCS Legacy Society, 2005 (Box 330, Folder 24)
  - Archives Prints (Box 330, Folder 25)
  - Old Photos (Box 330, Folder 26)
  - Pageant: AHEA Through The Years, 1959 (Box 330, Folder 27)
  - Centennial Plans, 2008 (Box 330, Folder 28)
  - Centennial, 2009 (Box 330, Folder 29)
  - Resources for the Centennial of AHEA/AAFCS - Compiled by Jenny Schroeder, 2009 (Box 338)
  - Project Identity and Recognize, 2003-2006 (Box 330, Folder 30)
  - Old Publications Catalogs, 1997-2001 (Box 331)
  - Miscellaneous Home Economics Jewelry (Box 331)
  - Photos of the artifacts/memorabilia that were shipped back to AAFCS Headquarters (Box 334)
  - History of Giving - includes donors names and amount given, Various Dates (Box 335)
  - Proposed library - AHEA Resources Committee, 1969 (Box 338)
  - Book Lists - Home Economics (Box 338)
  - AHEA Library Plans for Operation, 1970-1977 (Box 338)
  - AHEA Library - Self evaluation, 1974-04 (Box 338)
  - Membership Profile for Computer Data, 1977-1978 (Box 338)
  - AAFCS history, 2005-2009 (Box 338)